Jack Kotheimer

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PHONE: (708)-710-6649 PORTFOLIO: https://jackkotheimer.com

EMAIL: jkotheimer9@gmail.com GITHUB: https://github.com/jkotheimer

I am a firm believer in result-oriented work - It only took me three years to complete my undergraduate degree. That is not only because I set a goal to do so, but because I dug in and worked hard, all while remaining on the dean's list and creating projects with other developers as much as possible.

Languages	Frameworks	Databases	Tools
 Java C C++ Python Bash PHP SQL JavaScript HTML5/CSS3 	Apache CFXNode.jsFlaskDjangoHibernate	MySQLAmazon RDSMongoDB/AtlasFirebase	GitLinuxAWSSSHElasticBeanstalk

Education

Loyola University Chicago B.S. Software Engineering (Deans List)

May 2020

Work Experience

Back-end Developer Intern EzClinic Chicago, IL September 2020 – Current

- Reorganized source code repository and filtered out unnecessary and unsafe files
- Wrote bash scripts to automate the 3 main deployment mechanisms:
 - Local development & debugging server deployment
 - Remote staging server deployment using ElasticBeanstalk & test result fetching
 - Production server deployment using ElasticBeanstalk & CNAME swap
- Executed the migration from a local database to a remote database with a secure transfer of credentials upon deployment
- Completely decoupled server logic from client applications by refactoring to a REST api through the following means:
 - Wrote documentation outlining the I/O and application flow of a REST api that would serve the same functionality as before
 - Implemented the decoupling of each HTTP request one REST function at a time
 - Utilized the previously written staging script to test each update before being pushed to production
- Computer Science Tutor Loyola University Chicago Chicago, IL
 - Tutored Loyola Computer Science students on an appointment basis
 - Ensured high quality aid to all students both during and outside work hours

Research Assistant Loyola University Chicago Chicago, IL July 2019 – December 2019

November 2019 - May 2020

2018 - Current

February 2020 - May 2020

- Analyzed videos of CPS courses, ensuring curriculum and research standards were upheld
- Participated in a series of seminars determining the most effective educational techniques for computer science

Java Programming Instructor Digital Media Academy Chicago, IL June 2019 – August 2019

- Taught fundamentals of the Java programming language to high school students
- Focused on advocating problem solving strategies

Pianoboard

ChatApp

• Structured a curriculum with hands-on project based learning

Android Research Developer Loyola University Chicago Chicago, IL May 2019 – June 2019

- Collaborated with three other software engineers in person, full-time for a month
- Created customizable sign-language-based app for physically and vocally disabled people (see 'TalkMotion' under Project Experience tab)

Project Experience

1 Toject Emperione

https://jackkotheimer.com/projects/#pianoboard

https://jackkotheimer.com/projects/#chatapp

Created a RESTful web service to create music projects which store and process client-made MIDI recordings

- All CRUD operations occur in an isolated Node is API, completely uncoupled from the webpage server
- <u>Utilized</u>: PHP, Node.js, Apache HTTPD, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, MySQL, Bash, Git
- Developed a customer service based chatting application focused on programmatic database manipulation
- <u>Utilized</u>: Python, Flask, Jinja2, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, MySQL, Bash, Git

E-Commerce API https://jackkotheimer.com/projects/#ecommerce August 2019 – December 2019

- Built a RESTful API for a barebones e-commerce website
- <u>Utilized:</u> Java, Apache Server w/ CXF, Apache Maven, Junit, MySQL, Hibernate, AWS, Git

TalkMotion https://jackkotheimer.com/projects/#talkmotion May 2019 – June 2019

- Collaborated on an Android app to translate sensor readings from hand gestures to text-to-speech commands
- Utilized: Java, SQLite, Android Studio, object state machines, machine learning, Git